Guide to the Bruce Davidson Photograph Collection 1966-1968 PR 89
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Bruce Davidson Photograph Collection
1966-1968
PR 89
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
0.92 Linear feet (1 box)
The Bruce Davidson Photograph Collection consists of fourteen images taken between 1966 and 1968 in the neighborhood of East Harlem in New York City.
Provenance
Gift of Bruce Davidson, 2001.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to thirty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.
Scope and Content Note
The Bruce Davidson Photograph Collection consists of fourteen images taken between 1966 and 1968 in the neighborhood of East Harlem in New York City. Davidson embarked on an extensive documentary project of the neighborhood during those years, which was published in its entirety as "East 100th Street" (Cambridge, Mass., Harvard University Press, 1970). These photographs mainly document street activity, and particularly focus on children. The modern photographic prints are produced from the vintage negatives and signed on the verso by the photographer.
East Harlem (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Gelatin silver prints; New York (N.Y.); One-hundredth Street (New York, N.Y.)
  - [Waterfront Family and Hammock], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Children Looking Through Window with Chicken Wire], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Boy on Rooftop With Kite], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Girl on Couch with View of E. 100th Street], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Facade], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Women Seated Laughing], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Couple Dancing at Jukebox], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Woman in Kitchen with Madonna on Wall], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Boy With Pigeon], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [Woman Holding Newborn], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [Girls Playing Jump rope at Night], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [Group outside Atena's Grocery], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [Two Children Seated on Fire Escape], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - [Reflection of Man sitting at Restaurant Counter], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)